Ethan Lindsey

Ames, IA | (515)-619-8081 | ethan.james.lindsey@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/ejlindseycs | github.com/Ethan[Lindsey

Summary

Recent university graduate with aptitude for detailed analysis and logical reasoning. Strengths in math and computer theory proven by experience tutoring university students. Excels at roles in mathematical or scientific fields especially involved with computer programming. Interested in working with data analytics, modeling, and processing.

Education

B.S. in Computer Science; Minor in Music Technology

Iowa State University - GPA: 3.91

Experience

Computer Science Tutor

January 2022-December 2022

Iowa State University, Communications Building

Ames, IA

- Tutored 100+ clients on advanced programming practices and concepts.
- Collaborated with team of 10+ tutors to find solutions for complex problems.
- Presented debugging processes on 500+ errors with ~95% success rate.
- Applied solid understanding of third and fourth-year level concepts.

Student Worker

August 2021-December 2021

Iowa State University, Exam Accommodations Center

Ames, IA

- Proctored 100+ students while supplying personalized accommodations.
- Regularly evaluated sensitive confidential information discretely with integrity.
- Addressed 50+ critical issues with personalized solutions.

Projects

Anthill August 2022-December 2022

- Senior design team project created using Flutter and Firebase.
- Contributed ~60% of the code including authentication, profile, and dashboard.
- Improved performance and security by reviewing team contributions daily.
- Weekly sprints following Agile method using Jira.

Web Adventure

- 2D Web-based game made using JavaScript, Kotlin, Spring Boot, and MySQL.
- Used encapsulation and abstraction to decrease development time by ~50%
- User authentication using Spring Security and password encryption.

Ouack Manager

August 2020-December 2020 May 2020

- Team project using Java, Android Studio, MySQL and Spring Boot.
- Implemented 75% of front-end, including tasks, profile, login, and settings.
- Stored data locally for quick access both offline and online.

Technical Skills

Languages

Proficient

C/C++, Java, JavaScript, Dart, Python, MySQL

Familiar

Kotlin, PHP, C#

December 2022 Technologies

AWS, React, NumPy, Spring Boot, Firebase, Flutter, Node.js

Software

Excel, Docker, Android Studio

Soft Skills

Critical Analysis **Conflict Resolution Active Learning** Adaptability

Relevant Topics

Algorithm Design **Data Structures Computational Geometry Network Protocols Network Security**

Awards

July 2022 ISU Dean's List

December 2019-December 2022

Highest 2% LAS Freshman

Highest 2% LAS Junior

May 2021